{
  "year": 2017,
  "mcq": [
    {
      "prompt": "Which of the following statements are /is true for the SIA Building Contract (Lump Sum):\n\ni) The contract is a fixed price not subject to measurement or recalculation should the actual quantities of work and materials differ from estimates.\nii) It is c ompulsory that the Bill of Quantities shall form part of the contract documents\niii)Iterim Certificates issued by the Architect can be amended\niv)The Contractor is obligated to notify the Architect in writing within 14 days of any event or direction or instruction which he considers entitles him to an Extension of Time.",
      "optionA": "i & iii",
      "optionB": "ii & iii",
      "optionC": "i & iv",
      "optionD": "i only",
      "answer": "A",
      "explanation": "i - Correct - Article 8 SIA 2016 BUILDING CONTRACT Without Quantities (Article 8)\nii - Wrong - BQ is only for measurement contract\niii - Correct - Cl 31(4) Correcting Earlier Certificates  - SIA 2016 BUILDING CONTRACT Without Quantities\niv - Wrong - should be 28 days instead of 14 days “Cl 23(3)(a) The contractor shall notify the Architect in writing within 28 days of any event of Diretion or Instruction which he shall consider as entitling him to an EOT. This notice shall be condition precedent to granting an extension of time.”"
    },
    {
      "prompt": "Under the SIA Building Contract, Liquidated Damages are usually computed between the time of:",
      "optionA": "Completion Certificate and Termination of Delay Certificate",
      "optionB": "Delay Certificate and Termination of Delay Certificate",
      "optionC": "Delay Certificate and Maintenance Certificate",
      "optionD": "Completion Certificate and Final Certificate",
      "answer": "B",
      "explanation": "A -  Wrong, completion cert issue when the work done without affecting Employer's full enjoyment and occupation of the property Cl 22(5)(a)(ii) Outstanding works\nB - Correct- Cl 24(2) LD & 24(3) Termination of delay cert\nC - Wrong, maintenance cert issue end of DLP period\nD - Wrong"
    },
    {
      "prompt": "Which of the following is/are grounds for Extension of Time under the REDAS D&B Contract:\ni) A variation instructed by the Employer's Representative\nii) Delay in obtaining authorities' approvals\niii) Suspension of Works under Section 23 and 26 of the SOP Act\ni) Employer Termination of a Main Contractor's Qualified Person before TOP",
      "optionA": "iv only",
      "optionB": "i & iii only",
      "optionC": "ii & iii only",
      "optionD": "all of the above",
      "answer": "B",
      "explanation": "i -  Correct - Cl 16.1.1 Grounds for EOT\nii - Wrong - it is contractor responsibilities Cl 1.12.1 compliance with statues, regulations and laws\niii - Correct - Cl 31.1.1 suspension of works\niv - Cl 4.3.3 & 4.3.4 Qualified Design Professionals. The Contractor shall be fully liable for all acts, omissions and default of such qualified professionals/persons."
    },
    {
      "prompt": "Under the SIA Minor Works Contract, when does the Contractor submit a Payment Claim to the Employer?",
      "optionA": "14 days after the Architect's Interim Certificate has been issued",
      "optionB": "35 days after the Architect's Interim Certificate has been issued",
      "optionC": "Where the interim payment is based on periodic valuation, on the last day of each month",
      "optionD": "When he disputes the amount certified by the Architevt in his Interim Certificate",
      "answer": "D",
      "explanation": "D - Correct - CL 25 (1) (a) (iv) Payment claim"
    },
    {
      "prompt": "You are the Superintending Officer (SO) administering a PSSCOC Contract that has just r eceived Temporary Occupation Permit (TOP). You have just found out that one item was constructed without the issuance of a Superintending Officer Instruction (SOI). You should:\n\ni)Issue SOI\nii) Inform Contractor of oversight\niii) Obtain official variation approval from Employer\niv) Backdate all SOIs issued and re-issue in sequence",
      "optionA": "i only",
      "optionB": "i & iii only",
      "optionC": "i, ii & iii only",
      "optionD": "All of the above",
      "answer": "C",
      "explanation": "i -  Correct\nii - Correct - should inform (no clause mentioned to inform)\niii - Correct - any variation should get approval from client\niv - wrong - PSSCOC never mentioned can backdate / issue amendment like SIA"
    },
    {
      "prompt": "The Employer has terminated the employment of Main Contractor under the SIA Building Contract. The Contractor shall:\n\ni) Leave the site\nii) Submit Claim for Works completed to date\niii) Complete works that cannot be stopped midway due to safety issues\niv) Remove unused materials and equipment from site",
      "optionA": "i only",
      "optionB": "i & ii only",
      "optionC": "i, ii & iii only",
      "optionD": "All of the above",
      "answer": "B",
      "explanation": "i -  Correct - CL 32(1)(c)\nii - Correct - SOP act (can claim for works completed before C receive Termination Cert)\niii - Wrong- 33(2)(a) - terminate with immediate effect. The contractor may use the same reason to continue the work\niv - Wrong - Cl 32(4)(c)"
    },
    {
      "prompt": "Under the SIA Building Contract, which of the following must occur before the issuance of the Delay Certificate?",
      "optionA": "After the issuance of Completion Certificate",
      "optionB": "After the receipt of Temporary Occupation Permit (TOP) from the Building Construction Authority (BCA)",
      "optionC": "After the issuance of Final Certificate",
      "optionD": "After the assessment of all EOT and no further EOT matters are outstanding",
      "answer": "D",
      "explanation": "D - Correct - Cl 24(1)(a)(ii)"
    },
    {
      "prompt": "Under the SIA Minor Works Contract, which of the following is / are true with regards to the Certificate of Liquidated Damages Entitlement (CLDE)?\n\ni) Only one CLDE can be issued by the Architect after he/she has assessed all Extensions of Time.\nii) A CLDE states the number of days the Contractor is in default as well as the amount of liquidated damages the Employer is entitled to deduct.\niii) A CLDE is issued by the Employer when he wants to deduct liquidated damages.\niv) The Employer is obliged to deduct the amount certified by the Architect in the CLDE.",
      "optionA": "i and ii only",
      "optionB": "ii only",
      "optionC": "iii only",
      "optionD": "i, ii & iv only",
      "answer": "B",
      "explanation": "i -  Wrong - Cl 16 (8)\nii - Correct - Cl 16 (9) (a)\niii - Wrong - Cl 16 (8) Employer inform architect in writing to issue CLDE\niv - Wrong - Cl 16 (9) (b)"
    },
    {
      "prompt": "Under the PSSCOC, which of the following is true?",
      "optionA": "The Employer takes the risk for adverse physical conditions for sub-surface works",
      "optionB": "The Contractor is not entitled to claim for loss and expense if the Employer fails to give possession of the Site on or before the date stated in the Letter of Acceptance.",
      "optionC": "The Contractor is entiteld to terminate his employment if the Employer interferes with the certification of the Superintending Officer.",
      "optionD": "The Superintending Officer must be an Architect registered with the Board of Architects",
      "answer": "A",
      "explanation": "A -  Cl 5.2\nB - Wrong - Contractor is entitled to claim - Cl 12.3\nC - Wrong\nD - Wrong - can be anyone - Cl 1.1 (ab)"
    },
    {
      "prompt": "Under the REDAS D&B Contract, where the Employer is appointing his own Architect to provide and act as qualified person (QP) for the architectural design, which of the following is/are true?\n\ni) The Contractor is responsible for the sufficiency and correctness of the architectural design.\nii) The Contractor shall obtain all necessary approvals from the relecant authorities to enable the Employer's QP to obtain the Temporary Occupation Permit (TOP).\niii) The Employer's Representative cannot issue the Handing Over Certificate until TOP is obtained by the Employer's QP.\niv) If TOP is delayed by the Employer's QP, the Contractor is entitled to apply for extension of time.",
      "optionA": "i only",
      "optionB": "ii only",
      "optionC": "ii & iii only",
      "optionD": "all of the above",
      "answer": "D",
      "explanation": "i - Correct Cl 4.1.1\nii -Correct Cl 4.2.1\niii - Correct Cl 11.2.1.2\niv - Correct, Cl 16.1.3"
    }
  ],
  "essay": [
    {
      "title": "Question 2",
      "subtitle": "2.01",
      "mainQuestion": "State 5 key items you would include in the Contract Preliminaries and explain their importance",
      "subQuestions": [],
      "marks": [5]
    },
    {
      "title": "Question 2",
      "subtitle": "2.02",
      "mainQuestion": "You have been appointed as the Architect for a large and complex mixed used development next to an operation MRT Station.",
      "subQuestions": [
        "You have recommended that due to the complexity of the project in terms of specialist works / safety / scope etc., a Pre-Qualification process will ensure that the appropriate tenderers are selected for the subsequent tender.\n\nHighlight 5 Key Pre-Qualification criteria and explain their importance.",
        "The Pre-qualification exercise has been completed and the tenderers have been pre-qualified for the subsequent tender.\n\nWhat are the procedural measures that you would put in place to ensure that the subsequent tender would be fair and transparent, and best serve the project?",
        "The tender is now closed. Describe the subsequent process to evaluate the tenders using industry norms and criteria to evaluate the tender submissions.",
        "Prepare a Letter of Acceptance to the main contractor in a proper format, listing down the key items to be documented."
      ],
      "marks": [5, 3, 5, 12]
    },
    {
      "title": "Question 3",
      "subtitle": "3.01",
      "mainQuestion": "You are the Architect for a project administering the SIA Building Contract. The Employer  visits the site and gives orders directly to the Contractor to alter the Contractor's site operations and method of working claiming that it is better.\n\nIn your answers, please make references to the relevant Articles and Clauses.",
      "subQuestions": [
        "Is the Contractor obliged to comply? How would you advise the Employer?",
        "How would you address the situation?"
      ],
      "marks": [6, 4]
    },
    {
      "title": "Question 3",
      "subtitle": "3.02",
      "mainQuestion": "In the course of administering the Contract, some discrepancies were discovered. The contract drawings show 4 pavilions; however the Schedule of Works (SOW) states only 3 pavilions. The Contractor asserts that the fourth pavilion is a variation as he has based his pricing on the SOW, and requests for an Architect's Instruction (AI) to be issued.\n\nIn your answers please make reference to the relevant Articles and Clauses.",
      "subQuestions": [
        "How would you respond to the Contractor under the Lump Sum form?",
        "How would you respond to the Contractor under the Measurement form, where only 3 pavilions were stated in the Bill of Quantities (BQ)?"
      ],
      "marks": [3, 3]
    },
    {
      "title": "Question 3",
      "subtitle": "3.03",
      "mainQuestion": "",
      "subQuestions": [
        "How does the SIA Building Contract provide for cash flow to the Contractor?",
        "The Contractor is experiencing cash flow issues and requests for help from the Employer. The Employer instructs you to certify in the next Interim Certificate 'advance payment' to the Contractor.\n\nHow would you advise the Employer? Explain your reasons."
      ],
      "marks": [4, 10]
    },
    {
      "title": "Question 4",
      "subtitle": "4.01",
      "mainQuestion": "During the project site meeting, the Employer requested for additional works to be carried out. This was recorded in the minutes of meeting which also noted that EOT may be granted. The Contractor carried out the works on site immediately, and completed the task. Subsequently the Contractor submitted the notice for Extension of Time (EOT) after 2 months.",
      "subQuestions": [
        "Under the SIA Building Contract, is the Contractor entitled to the EOT assessment? Please cite the relevant clause(s) to support your argument.",
        "When does the Architect have to determine the period of EOT?",
        "You requested for more information from the Contractor to assess the EOT. After 28 days the Contractor has still failed to provide the information.\n\nWhat is your next course of action? Explain your reasons",
        "While you are in the midst of assessing the EOT claims based on your own available information, the contractor subsequently submits additional relevant information after the 28 days has passed, stating that the delay is due to the Employer's direct contractor. Explain your next course of action?"
      ],
      "marks": [6, 3, 3, 4]
    },
    {
      "title": "Question 5",
      "subtitle": "5.01",
      "mainQuestion": "You are the Architect for an Office Building and the contract used is the SIA Building Contract. The Completion Certificate has been issued.",
      "subQuestions": [
        "During the Maintenance Period, under what circumstances can Architect's Directions (AD) and Architects's Instructions (AI) be issued? Please cite the relevant clauses to support your answer",
        "6 months into the Maintenance Period, the Employer wanted to add new solar panels on the roof of the Office and requests you to issue an Architect's Instruction for the works to the Contractor.\n\nHow would you advise the Employer on the contractual process to enable the solar panels to be installed on the roof of the warehouse?"
      ],
      "marks": [4, 9]
    },
    {
      "title": "Question 5",
      "subtitle": "5.02",
      "mainQuestion": "You are the Architect for an Office Building and the contract used is the SIA Building Contract. The Completion Certificate has been issued.\n\n1 month before the end of the Maintenance period, it was discovered that there were water leakages on several panes of curtain wall glass. It was ascertained that some of the gaskets on the curtain wall system were not properly installed and the Contractor would need to replace them. The rectification work will take 3 months due to its complexity.",
      "subQuestions": [
        "Under the above circumstances, when should you issue the Maintenance Certificate? Explain your answer.",
        "What are the implications if you do not issue the Maintenance Certificate on time?"
      ],
      "marks": [8, 3]
    },
    {
      "title": "Question 5",
      "subtitle": "5.03",
      "mainQuestion": "You are the Architect for an Office Building and the contract used is the SIA Building Contract. The Completion Certificate has been issued.\n\nPrior to the issuance of the Maintenance Certificate, the Contractor submits his Final Account Document to you.\n\nWhat are your obligations as an Architect?",
      "subQuestions": [],
      "marks": [6]
    }
  ]
}
